<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Bagnaram Blog</title><link>http://example.org/</link><description>Recent content on Bagnaram Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kube Sticky Project</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2021-07-07-kube-project/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2021-07-07-kube-project/</guid><description>One of the main things I missed going from RedHat Openshift to vanilla Kubernetes is the concept of switching projects. An Openshift project is simply a context associated with a particular namespace. However projects/namespaces can be switched and all subsequent commands will inherit that namespace scope. This saves me the trouble of attaching -n namespace to each and every command. I decided to write a quick and dirty ZSH plugin to take care of this by adding a kubectl project command.</description></item><item><title>Building a Keyboard From Scratch</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2020-12-01-keyboard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2020-12-01-keyboard/</guid><description>This article was typed using the finished keyboard. Mechanical keyboards are all the rage today. Having a solid typing experience has never been as important to me as I have realized now. Often we are left to our squishy laptop keyboards, and they do get the job done. However, recently I have started to realize that a good keyboard is comparable to a good set of tires for a car, or good running shoes.</description></item><item><title>Century Ride With a Twist</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2020-10-19-century-ride/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2020-10-19-century-ride/</guid><description>This weekend I decided to do another century ride on the cycle. I currently ride an early 80s Panasonic Sport LX. This ride will take me through some beautiful hilly areas in central Texas. This trip was a little different though. I&amp;rsquo;ve been getting into botanising lately, and this trip was going to be a way to get out and make some plant observations while on the bike ride.
After listening to the podcast Crime Pays but Botany Doesn&amp;rsquo;t, I became inspired to become more familiar with the landscape we live in.</description></item><item><title>Primitive Camping &amp; Working</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2020-09-11-camping/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2020-09-11-camping/</guid><description>This summer has not been your average one. With a quarantine upon us, and a friend from Europe who planned a short visit turning into an entire summer stay! Anyhow, we were chatting and thought a camping trip would be a lot of fun and a great way to spend some time outside. With the summer months ahead, we prepared for the planned two-week trip of primitive camping across the US states of Colorado and Utah.</description></item><item><title>NixOS &amp; Enlightenment</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2020-06-20-nix-enlightenment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2020-06-20-nix-enlightenment/</guid><description>NixOS is the latest and greatest in terms of system configuration management. Think of how configuration management tools like Ansible or Packer.io allow you to define the run-time configuration of you machine in a state-ful way. Combine that with the power of what is the Nix package manager, and you have a Linux distribution that follows this model for configuring the entire system.
My Nixos/Enlightenment desktop.
NixOS Experience I decided to test drive NixOS and see what I thought.</description></item><item><title>JenkinsX on Kubernetes Cluster-API</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2020-03-23-capa/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2020-03-23-capa/</guid><description>JenkinsX is the next iteration of the Jenkins CI engine that is geared towards a cloud-native kubernetes setting. Instead of the more broad approach taken previously, JenkinsX focuses on Kubernetes native continuous-integration by relying on an engine Tekton to define its jobs and pipelines inside of kubernetes.
Cluster-API AWS I&amp;rsquo;m using CAPA Cluster-API provider for AWS as my workload Kubernetes cluster. I manage this cluster locally with a control plane defined using Kind.</description></item><item><title>Tour de Taiwan Part 2</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2019-10-26-taiwan-japan-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2019-10-26-taiwan-japan-2/</guid><description>This is a continuation of the Taiwan bicycling trip. It commences as a direct flight from Taipei to Osaka. The trip was designated an exploratory adventure in Japan, and it was convenient because the flight connection allowed this leg of the journey to take place. I likely would have not included Japan in the itinerary but because I had been given a great deal with ANA Airlines, this was made possible.</description></item><item><title>Tour de Taiwan</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2019-10-18-taiwan-japan/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2019-10-18-taiwan-japan/</guid><description>This is a Giant Cycling Adventures trip that was inspired from my first trip to Taiwan and biking the countryside. This trip is a formal tour that circles the entire island!
Day 1 - Starting in Florida My trip began as a business trip in Tampa. I woke up around 4AM and caught a taxi to the airport to get on a flight Houston. The trip connected in Houston and then to Japan via ANA Airlines.</description></item><item><title>Halifax</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2019-06-16-halifax/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2019-06-16-halifax/</guid><description>A weekend trip to Canada! This adventure was another cycling-inspired trip that had me visiting the beautiful Canadian province of Nova Scotia. After hearing about the terrific cycling infrastructure in the Halifax area, I decided it was well worth a trip up for a long weekend. At the time I was traveling for business to the Washington D.C. area, and I was already booking travel every weekend. This was a great opportunity, because I was already on the east coast, so Halifax was not to difficult to get to.</description></item><item><title>Deutschland</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2019-02-09-germany/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2019-02-09-germany/</guid><description>My trip to Germany was inspired from a 3 year study of German in school. I had decided to take a holiday in the early part of 2019 because I had holidays to use up of else they would be taken away! Because of this, I decided to book a trip to someplace in Europe. Because I also have a friend that lives in Germany, I decided it would be nice to visit her too.</description></item><item><title>Portland Weekend</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-06-02-portland/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-06-02-portland/</guid><description>Planning &amp;amp; Prep After taking a trip to Iceland with my brother and friend, we began looking at the next adventure. This time, we decided to keep it inside of the country. We also kept the trip duration to a 4 days over a long weekend. The plan was to visit the Pacific coast and concentrate around Portland Oregon. Since we had already gone through the experience of booking an inter nation trip, this turn would be much easier.</description></item><item><title>My trip to Taiwan and Việt Nam - Closing</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-04-07-taiwan-vietnam-wrapup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-04-07-taiwan-vietnam-wrapup/</guid><description>Closing Remarks &amp;amp; Wrap-up I spent some of that flight writing up this blog post, listening to music, and sleeping. It has been a fulfilling but tiring two weeks. I need some time to process everything. As I write this memoir of such a life-changing trip, I cannot but stop and think about what a blessing this opportunity was. The ability to visit such a different place. The process of trusting despite the unknown.</description></item><item><title>My trip to Taiwan and Việt Nam - Part 2</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-03-31-taiwan-vietnam-2/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-03-31-taiwan-vietnam-2/</guid><description>Day 7 Taiwan The last day in Vietnam. I awoke early at Giang&amp;rsquo;s, ate some chè for breakfast, and left 6AM via grab to Sân Bay Nội Bài. I arrived at the airport, and found the ticket check-in. I thought I was going to be late since I had to check my box of goodies I acquired in Vietnam. I spoke to a lady while I was in line and she directed me to the front so I can check in.</description></item><item><title>My trip to Taiwan and Việt Nam</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2018-03-30-taiwan-vietnam/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2018-03-30-taiwan-vietnam/</guid><description>Well. Finally got around to putting this old website together. Neat thing about it - powered by Jekyll and I can use Markdown to author my posts. It actually is a lot easier than I thought it was going to be.
Preparing for Travel Last year I finally bit the bullet and decided make it a goal to do a major trip each year. Part of the mentality, required me to step out of my comfort zone of life and routine, and just go for it!</description></item><item><title>Iceland Trip</title><link>http://example.org/posts/2017-05-01-iceland/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://example.org/posts/2017-05-01-iceland/</guid><description>Iceland Trip We took a vacation to Iceland over April 26 to May 6th. The idea to take the trip was motivated by a desire to experience something fresh with friends and to explore a new area for the first time. This would be the first real vacation I had gone on through our own planning and idea. I decided to begin research as I was made aware of the cheap flights to Scandinavia through WOW Airlines by a friend.</description></item></channel></rss>