<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mexico on Bagnaram Blog</title><link>https://bagnaram.github.io/categories/mexico/</link><description>Bagnaram Blog (mexico)</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bagnaram.github.io/categories/mexico/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mexico Trip - Oaxaca</title><link>https://bagnaram.github.io/posts/2022-08-09-mexico/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bagnaram.github.io/posts/2022-08-09-mexico/</guid><description>
&lt;p>
This summer I decided to take a trip to Mexico with some friends. It was not
your average MX trip either! We were going for the Gueleguetza festival in
Oaxaca. This is the interior of the country and contains a rich culture. I had
always known Oaxaca for the many agave that grow in the region, and being a
center for Mezcal production. However after some initial research, I found the
area to be very physically active and even boasts some of the top performing
athletes including trail running. This would be the perfect combination! A
run-cation!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Preparation for the trip began by planing for a pet sitter for my dog. This
would be the first large trip I would take which I could not bring the dog. I
stumbled across &lt;a href="http://trustedhousesitters.com/">Trusted House Sitters&lt;/a> from a recent Couch Surfing guest. I
listed my place, and after some patience I found a pet sitter, so I could secure
the trip!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
I also reached out to some local sport groups through Couch Surfing and was put
in touch with a running group called OAX Sport. I contacted their staff and
signed up for some runs and even a trail race during my stay!&lt;/p>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-1" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-1">
Arrival in Oaxaca
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-1" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>I arrived in Oaxaca Mexico in the morning and quickly entered the country
through customs. Already, I felt the feeling of being in a new foreign place. It
has been so long since experiencing that feeling. I took some cash from the ATM
and struggled with my little Spanish to make change for the bus. As I exited the
Airport on foot, I walked into the countryside that I would know as Zapoteca or
Oaxaca! My first lesson was that taking the bus requires signaling for a stop.
There are no real bus stops in the area and this caused me to miss it. I
followed up by hopping into a red looking taxi that I kept seeing people enter.
Turns out these are called collectivo taxis and they are a great way to get
around Oaxaca. It is a red taxi with a lettering on the front glass such as &amp;#34;El
Centro&amp;#34; which is where i wanted to go. I proceeded to enter the front seat with
random people and shared the front seat making it an overfull car experience. I
reached Oaxaca and paid my 45 peso fare and began the walk through this Spanish
colonial city to my accommodation. I was staying at a hostel in the part of town
near the Guelegueta stadium. I reached, checked in, and dropped my belongings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Immediately I was blown away by the culture, architecture, and street food.
Because the Gueleguetza festival was upon, the street was lined with many
street food vendors and also many boutique vendors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
I ended the day by enjoying a relaxing drink of mezcal at a nearby mezcaleria
Casa Convite.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/1KpL2u43AqWh2cXbA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEX3nQWZspMytiKwVo6dl7Fdm2P342LHhxRuxmtojf1F1NFCDHcffkHFYDDJyqwp356C6lYzl8eOUnfBDr0Cq99oJzHVa6YwvxauTbHxiH382kOVioW8u4wwOx4iDTkSwrtyMcTiWbBEG6JtIPyEzYH2=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Welcome" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-2" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-2">
Day 1
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-2" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>I woke up early to join the OAX Sports team for their track workout. This was
across the town at a university campus. I decided I would jog there across the
town. It was still dark and I reached what looked like a seemingly abandoned
track field. After circling the complex a few times I started notice runners
entering inside through a gap in the fence. As I began to notice this I joined
them and entered the track complex and met my training team. The track workout
was all voluntary and I was able to meet some great people from OAX Sports and
made a connection that would last the portion of the trip!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
After the workout, I returned to my hostel to have breakfast, and then do a
fantastic introductory walking tour of the city of Oaxaca. On this tour we
visited an Organic Mercado, El Centro main square, the Gueleguetza venue on top
of the hill, tried some ice cream with Tuna(Nopal fruit), Tacos, and even saw
the aqueduct that Nacho Libre was shot!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/xm7HBhNGedyTNYgZ8">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEWpkkH86JGYq2ptJhqVmsD6t6-Ib9-wpJ42CST1FLtCWKXnaKdfyQbYnX3aMT0yZ1gjQyKcPf6RP1eb2Tt_GbFI57DfdccCbYqu9dsKgIi_5rJ0PC2nYvCm7nUsTVRJ-Yc27gAlxoGSyfnDtMeQH7Of=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Aqueduct" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
We also entered both of the enormous Mercados. Mercado Benito Juarez and Mercado
20 de November. These places are enormous! The is the full experience I wanted
by walking through the halls of a giant market and getting lost weth countless
vendors selling things like mole, jugos naturales, mezcal, street food, and even
regular household goods!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/S68hYT4JundEosieA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEViMD5DMhp5oqibD6VCRuHwbpJR9CDH9xD44-3E4hS8R7AVaJIz2GyMj0NCADtY_V6yzWs8aJD8ndhGhTVJbDxnQchWb0Lc6O_hLrMKbIoZWG8HtNI44OhRArnq3CPnQJsR07aClAiqLnAGDV4hTnjA=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="View of Oaxaca" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
I also came to know a fantastic cacao drink called tejate. This chocolately
drink consists of cacao blossom, mamey seed &amp;amp; coriu cacao. It has a foam on the
surface that makes for a delicious and refreshing drink.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/pKnhV9yXdg6ai6si7">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEWbSWf1qsOE4KC_1FMK4CDDLRi7CnmveHsnEcz-kJWoLVaYjnJ5BpwoaheCqSv3vpcnwqEMNqiFonA0PdwK-ctoLZIihxZm0ArYAT4ZYuK_r2yz5Ex1j2mxx2lNa2tUX2n0-_xCemM4dB0cS1DZcCJf=w658-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Tejate" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
That night I met up with the local Couchsurfing group in Oaxaca and joined them
at the Feria de Mezcal. This is a massive Mezcal trade show and party located in
the Oaxaca convention center. I came to meet some great friends in this CS
community and we rode together to the festival. In fact on the ride over to the
festival, I also met a great friend randomly by chatting on the bus!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
The Mezcal festival also featured a street food festival and we began by filling
our stomach before the alchahol! There I tried some more tejate, and a tostada
with two tortillas instead of one. Quite delicious.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
The mezcal show itself had many vendors and we could sample each type of mezcal.
The vendors featured a variety of agave (Maguey) drinks such as espadin,
tobalar, coyote, and tepistate. The event had a dance floor where a band was
playing some traditional and norteno music and towards the end of the day we had
entered the dance floor and danced into the night until the event was over! We
finished the night by walking back and trying some street elote.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-3" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-3">
Day 2
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-3" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>
The day started with a trail run with the OAX sport group. They were going to
Sierra Norte to trail run in the Ixtepeji Autonomous Region. We met early in the
morning and I rode with the OAX Sport staff into the heights of the Sierra
Norte, a mountain range just north of Oaxaca. We entered a different climate
with tall trees and some magnificent large agaves. We were planning a trail run
because the next day was the trail race. This mountain is indigenous land, and
is not public so we needed to ask permission from the local government. There
was an agreement that the trails may be used for this purpose and we entered the
park. The trail run began on some single track through an open range area. What
a great and beautiful course. I ran around 20k in total in around 2 hours and we
returned tired and hungry. Just in time for some breakfast at a rural mountain
restaurant on the way back down the mountain. There I had some traditional hot
chocolate and some carne asada that was very satisfying after the run!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/6PAVATX7NRNE2aov5">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEUVNkB2S7oTf_-KIDVHfxgzx3NFN6qUGbW40YhFhjXMigNqr5xdRY57pIbdl4W8PsKCUuSumM9A1bYnyiO_ByWIqxrLDou-nKzM5FHWtD9zBxyqi8ZaW50xOZK2nIIDl7I1bq3FAMXYXJ1afobcy_EQ=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Open Range" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
After the run I had some free time until meeting the Couchsurfing group for a
Gueleguetza parade in downtown Oaxaca. This parade was starting at 7PM but the
CS group suggested meeting a few hours early to get a spot. Luckily I did
because the street really filled up. Best thing is that I was recommended to get
a mezcal glass made out of bamboo because the parade would offer free mezcal to
the spectators! This is not something I would have ever expected. As the parade
began, I saw my first glimpse of the Gueleguetza festivities. The parade
featured fireworks, costumes, marching bands and each region of the Oaxaca
region showcasing their culture!&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="512" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/XLdpJU8psdY?list=PLVXoDcbm8YOw7WKfiBtx8pKDWlLG7p_AV" title="Feria de Gueleguetza 2022" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>
That evening was a free salsa dance lesson put on by my hostel. Now I was a true
beginner but it was truly a great experience that I was able to join and learn
making it a great time!&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-4" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-4">
Day 3 - Race Day
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-4" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>The day started out early again as I met the OAX Sport staff to join them on the
Cerro Negro Mountain Race. This race takes place in Mixteca, a region outside of
the city of Oaxaca. I rode in one of the staff members car, leaving at around 6
AM. It was an absolutely scenic ride though some desert and mountains until
reaching the puebla of Magdalena Yodocono de Porfirio Díaz. We reached the start
of the race and were ready to start the 12k at around 8AM.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.google.com/share/AF1QipMvPtkghHsWVyks_J9R31N-lnlu2YpgmeQx0QvUDMDkY2qxrt1DPYO40A1V2kIvQg/photo/AF1QipO9ePYipUrDoQojq2BajDBDVPK8iitBK-W9Vz-G?key=d3Z1X3RRZl9STlpPbDlSTFlZcUU0QzlZbkFIOFhR">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEV9Wu0EEbdlYGYtun2PIJZmzuiBeB_QO__NCsp3eY_CWQ549tNBI6tlr-VQ-hNV9xpBB4ONrdq31zGBj8YqenWNRP2HHnX2FJXrTyotqSG7RGvdHg9iA2qJ3MyoJR8_Cyz6Oqt44d8jUA8rV3jLvH4z=w1170-h877-no"
alt="Welcome" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
The race course took us up the side of a large set of hills, through the trails
and forest on top, down the back of the hill, through some mountainside, and
through a desert area and back into town. What a difficult course! This trail
run was incredibly steep in certain parts going up resorting me to hiking it,
and some steep downhill sections. The locals who lived these mountains their
whole lives wore zooming past me at this point and gave me a newer level of
respect for the mountain natives!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/gEF74Afjv9zyiJ1v9">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEWPHyaCrpR9iTaalHmRAFoz6fWy68ob_-XwXUNwanz7NH03YvY0B4ehQdCMrg04OMjVVL_HqKYE8Yx8ELuml_KokCdLzYrrSThNqQgeMupbJ2NtOTnWjBegEYpHgGjFxKavktKOel5kB0mfabnd5Q9U=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="View From Hilltop" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
We finished the race, which actually turned out to be 18k instead of 12k and
they had some festivities as well as some great street food in the little
village. I ended up meeting a new friend from Chicago, living in the Mixteca
area and we shared some Mezcal he invited me to try in a little tienda. We
waited for all the racers to finish celebrated by cheering the winners of each
event. I was also able to meet some of the atheletes racing in this event! After
trying some street tacos and purchasing some Kamkoco snacks from a local vendor,
we headed out for a final photo and departed the Mixteca region back to Oaxaca.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/U39T5qzNyYxSw4Nf6">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEWuRe2a3olE-lDf19WT2E7MqIk67zXmy3OGHaWep8tkWBTbO_Zts466-LdPof22smAcIkpPqfqOIrgMNPvwsmhr8lzQf_bICtV9d3Q5wxddHPCOOJNYPBZLFPOlMftmeYVx6q6hnJDBvXwzHgF3J66G=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="View From Hilltop" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
I headed back to my hostel to check out and I would meet my friends who I would
be staying with the rest of the trip. This would be in a shared accommodation. I
located the place and checked into what seemed like a lavish Oaxaca estate
complete with a central outdoor room with bedrooms and kitchen encircling the
space. The place had a distinct spanish colonial feel with tiles and tall
ceilings. A true Oaxaca experience!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
After freshening up I joined my friend from OAX Sport for a a walk around the
city of Oaxaca and some good hangout time! We explored some parts of town such
as Reforma, a cafe, and even some of the campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-5" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-5">
Day 4 - Gueleguetza
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-5" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>A friend and I decided to visit the Gueleguetza performance. Not the main one
because tickets were being given out first-come meaning an incredibly long line
to wait! We visited a secondary Gueleguetza taking place in the Estadio
Tecnológico. This secondary performance was free admission and a very impressive
experience. What a rich cultural showcase with each region of Oaxaca
representing its own dance! It is best shown in video form!&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="512" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/KRwuWQQpXCE" title="Gueleguetza 2022 Danza de la Pluma" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>
The festival lasted around 4 hours with breaks for Micheladas and some snacks!
Afterwards was sort of a free day. I met with a running friend Edith who ran her
own artisinal mezcaleria. She was running with us at OAX Sport. I also visited
some of the mercados for a second time and had some street food that evening!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/atksmaRW91pxjCs37p">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEXA7GHyJzTuO_GH7zjJn0x9uvCdzXsdmwyFlM5TV89B1yyBQAy6f9Y7OARQV28b-Yn4w_bdyRgJFl4nAwULxgearnlsN2FvEp8rDBLz4RCn06YPmZ23xnLXCOlU0B7tLzynHvV4QUkoqNw3ER33QXL4=w658-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Free Mezcal" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-6" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-6">
Day 5
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-6" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>We started the day off very early for our mezcal hike and tour to Hierve el Agua
a set of rock formations in San Lorenzo Albarradas, Oaxaca. This tour was
through a group known as COYOTE Adventures that my friends arranged. This was
definitely a highlight of the trip. We started in a caravan that took us to the
natural park area and we hiked and explored the wonderful rock formations. We
even were able to swim in a few of the pools as a refreshment!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
The tour took us onto a journey of discovery of many of the agave and tree
species in the area! This was truly a great ecotourist experience and I found
myself fascinated in many of these species. The tour progressed into a
mezcaleria and artisinal tour of a few of the smaller scale mezcal growers and
distillers. This sgave us a personal connection to the people who produced the
mezcal and it was a great way to directly support them. In fact, we even were
given a tour of a distillery and shown the process that it is made. After, we
were invited as guests into the family&amp;#39;s home for a meal. That was a very nice
touch that I will always remember.&lt;/p>
&lt;script src="https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/publicalbum@latest/embed-ui.min.js" async>&lt;/script>
&lt;div class="pa-gallery-player-widget" style="width:100%; height:480px; display:none;"
data-link="https://photos.app.goo.gl/8fJedAQvv5eNQC4s8"
data-title="Mexico 2022 Oaxaca Mezcal Tour"
data-description="33 new items added to shared album">
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cZD-DrQmBROtq_qiyXfISMYfiBke0WC_BLxLx357arcdHaW96VZO9rzPUYs_QClujqCdLqmnoV0fzSd-_cHuK8Kxa0P7knzvKhSbxInssxa8hTHyEuZ5UT-Ltm7RoE_ifgjHOm4zVA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7mcLFkPTIIL7mQ8L_o3Ytitep6YvatEi8gPLtdFvwxe4Pv-nnolUtq6b-5_tu7BVhbr01nDsdjSizVeMczudQD6hi9N8iEq56bparQ9R4Qbjqrpxr9wyjbkabUl5d5JYdoekg3RONQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lC9bOJ2Sx1EPXIqo-6AD8VKvRbw2E-0nx9UEFfSSJs9c5nV7TgxPUD2Y5voW4Z1nBZXf0assITdl03D_ZDpyuxmDbQ3HWXmqNfUhAAAE8RWQYb87gUEBkg92NixGpuAK40fWNSjITQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UGx8e9TCFHcCYZx5X8T36w9VFIUUEelwOeKmveVw2Ua6LLEdZUX7mc8qqEqcPEg_K1ADHtNh_Dy6NvuVzAh475rvk7tNi5MfSPLMugeWb8vyPKOQJrfNCMli7-WcE5caUIlunwsp_w=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/X7A52M-7CKG4oRUOwOeHXsnhZcxh9VJeSeNV78NSqnA9EpzE4oKzck7bG5AEInhqeRpbNWJjou-ksQ7o_uLgwqWk-XDgQnsBvzK9j04M25FOke2OdSWwnbA0m5Fo_5egXjORFOOEaQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/OpR9ySLZAqqHh4Hds9bH69CQ-2_H-hIhuIMwmC3oGaBIraFxv4f6jOI3C-adV6eGfFTXJPLOEXxHfefaanBwE7ePQyKzSgPsj_6gU38_IYD9NoXD6niKIwIe2Hsp3udDNQKPJ7z7Jw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/O6K9XfFmpmaYfvg_EMkDfhxGsZ1s0lPDA3qt28SW5F_rlDTS-tdkI9ZfTcgHE7qpW36gXxdV8UVW1vU85bcBbvrq1M-F5Ojry4fXRKvK5scPwL__waj8LDIhMfrMt_FSaoc-KDhTpQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cuOdWfQ5qMkymWZEH3RyUNu7_9iHQC2AYXLtd_mlfd_Op3WPmsR8QjD4ivo5i7kmEMeLrj0tNEQcSxp7Zlimv_50PhlnD2bPybf78p1INH1aZteapu0LzHTdt7Q0FUlCgPP68iNn7Q=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/BGuafwatq1llNgCgW2D7_IG-F2UABFz1snwr1y1jkNEYOoddZTgmcr9tSdyUv5odsDdskCmAxs_untALa81OB1S4UEFmmEh9ctu8n74f7AY4jo_xm9SuawRJFj6Vsy9ar3Ai0KJcJw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/qSsRzpxe6xnkR_D8Rk5YumKrdymkucL80JNPZnxD1wzdeXIvRln-hSjTom-gSIrat7X-TTnVmYNSGYFQKMDwO1p4m8B0aX_McVhuHlKqbqvBbvhxs6THzxFM-6jvR8yGIG2hjA1ZjQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/_Muw5V5-BzYcQYhtrvYfj4w-_pIGJGcUzJYcsA-q7gPZ7FXEQMvJ3OLD8547cbp0jWt7rLxU1dUHyXEWwbbNcdbYZzokC3uKVJw9cqlgmmXOtZF9OaL46SF88GrvYb3JKpM_0esXhA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/CjxdGkEgT5uhUJeif1cRej-vuqwlmABGKWAsQJW7FevKWXA8TkMLKVMhB-C_LiO5gEzACPmSzlJ3RM04Pbvzr74HIPOWmFpYT6FzUX51Rt8Ca32-MbGI-waLX-JBxCDHKRYv7WK_Vw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/-oBud6dCP4hW2Jy0hb6reYcP2_yznDCU7qBvxPqtfv8nUfP_BZYCVIfLRs6iEEaWBqRyWz8tUTqYe2Q15BxpgT1CrjyRvHn9L5P-wJo3h2bP8hgbEWJWnsXSla_ya2LrZ9pJgBnDHg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/eIcsnvSHjLW9u6uh-IsZMnML2Yg6CbgkOgir2cIHbF0H8nO1hLyLvssxWzEfWsfWY0KnyW66g7FwyT0KIjUqkq4YlR5LeuAKK2LZ3JjvXZyfltcT89cxrxF2-wZLRq313NvGFyr5lg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/VsNAdjxo-XSDv6Dtlt_nktQ5WAEQqpxRb-dtkymeuYWsFbCZ-9UAkAgxfERb6awpqsea3nT4_Pn2SO0P-lv199RaQL7biVYF3ZdgooxTuvFtOBXec8E3fyt5-1gQA-FROMRrLeuQLw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/2FcVQTaOi1QCcAjc0wXzmz2Cld-HrfuWe5omE_bUOo-RgbfUAFk_YoafsEFJI5DgeQ696uOjjE1q1xnFWhZEUaqbwbOYfAB_uPmSq34xw87MXytarmGR7cDMw2-4XQ_IG0-UNWEFFA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/cPQi89AUubjPwof9-xmnAnAh1XSKFDbKuBxlOCZldz9CPh75KIEqtG4au2q9djSgEGCTjcygAhUP6_q-cmc1uKeDZjY5y5I6cBZluIOdSW4VjdFufbhsPRklEzhTcI3PErtBl7j8oQ=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/UoAy8J0zBoLqlhfctXe1LGYhJSmd6iss1JAOM4nHuOFnUQExACPb2XrNrZBN6pdY3YivddyF1_K9_wQQi5N4U7DEaES-oDEQU4Vu-45EQpN8KPsZq5dgs_AHzmKdJ-ZKDPg_kQMszg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/W4jBFLGf5VT591DO6DF5qQmOXJmkYqg64o9oPysAgcQL6U_TWcc8Mdtj8ppYWaPRqpIaPdwVIpSdrz5rFlIWyCojpsgYtDuf9J1r0bgL8j9-dUny-i3V8r6esiYk-vkb3GimGv5bCw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/tmX1JXsX4O22q5ksySttRKos5cAdDAP0U3BXvl8PZzCR-gp3qDaNYFnQ-2R8MYqTzoqwgrDDr-a7KL70QwXxpAr3QrsGSwO3_5xsEhUx9_6a9HbMTAiF3ga1LGLEBz-jAbNAod870w=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/YTOE6Td0A1sreyckSpTJYGledEZai6mABVmaJQeuH77nwNxAJqkgqSSU5O_c3mz5Yh62knoMBozcePmo-q_bi-KgdEiad8p8HpiaIFWMfayzSHxKZWE0-8W3464w0pwRU-hwfg8jSA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6dgSobIvBTUnvHWZG0S6D-9BjTds_END0beeM0Jp6QAsIX40OdRwjDKjD-GoTiLr7OWi75Yn0Qk3DVcZNsnsaArzukT4ZcDNuejkEonNCGiCTR_Lsl4t36apBdGM3snQLrE2lo6rAA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/7X-9kxpmcyQRsslvspgyT1-sKeW8tLGzMrizSEHgKYIBE_ldBiFDOn7AX5JEKNJque6QpjeYzNYBfiYsICucoKO2UzPqNl0tagv7PKlT7P1t34XTh8t7Bsl3LgnQxL2t3qdEAiSA8A=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/chwONiH6ImLkF73sc1mDXM3BW_ELzDE0u0yO2sSmwjWsBn1Ux1H-iNn42B4WJkO2cHlcAPAhnPvc1kKGXsDHT7Ej_BrKDrDbLPTvwh2DkA6adgJxyeCTAOnq682NK-upF7H9mZABhA=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/A2U4gyXyehBV7nPg58YQaKK1WShDellIQaNW0VXL9Sz05EJirStiXN24bUBDr1YLt2MIrGRhW-Nqh94r6OeLNDhYQ46VmoL5AfoNnMlUh9i9NIyGSlw86SoABduJNTIlLX8vdxRgrg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/m7E6je2P6H2kAauWzgumlDK6xvudzhl04q37_33GCd4oX52kuM3t99AYk14th8l7lkAgQgNzuSinlUuVNskow5XJtmM0VfACTbBBpJtK0MZNvsBYTY9y6OogfNdOcL4-EmXB85ofRw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/P94FRkaaCK5US5iY0mcsMjA9l1k8NTQRs1_ZUiP17_PFCFIG9eTiXCnFICfK0GA8izdsdbb7tOpVldb5teINl3omnEu0ZxhcCAQ0cuQyuAz5-LMr_suMojHKI2SeAtduCzm_dkBHQw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/v-Az-NL4jD2kD2nlGGtqvsrSPay8CtLyquWqWM87OQL2x1rZ35S4_GY6PifMaimZ_D7Ikd0VhZ0646Od1kMf5pcPqEhbwDwPkZKCTqk3Uuu1WEDoCF1O6j6gtAja088589FgFSc0Jw=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/Iq-F8GA6avF3zs9RxrpQpzHt8azfPl-zYoBm4XViYVFduIizZz5yrNCKHA7Mu177zCtWoO6f83yRlT49A3cSQNEKZjWeQDiVGDllJMiekg929OIOlacwu5Aqnc8rYjZJhTKkKhXk5A=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/s4NXOMm2RqXDE0jsEIgJVFAP6Zs23WBeh6sslTwUadPPUjmVUg8QJGsii23M6ZXoxZBJRB8y4fbgk8mcquaY4GyL2nWbeaToUPkrltCKc7VMfQEv1P4jriwPQOUCV2zZzhZcWCyq3A=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/j34pKBOEIAjyv3qBI_rbimNuFalKJYxc18FRdRvn7kuyJnHvB8HRA5Mh-9DR2pnCx2EeqSDAuxTNv5hEkmTHiqtDPDHb7_fq-sR8Q-hmqJ-kmKJ9e-BxEjAla-nnoexvMa9hfF2xrg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/xRVtE0XI6t7-ASofekXRVD4oMSt5PjMs5fxbBLSqwinizetroC1yNn1N0OZGV2MGRtW9mLuVAMVZL8SEuD_D9rO9ENhRlhF8ELBLPk68EUwil5_YJdHVUc2P6pm6YuuapkCSDQI0hg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;object data="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/TJk6ZQX7a7YM8MoGBFHFjxfcfMiaN9Yl9RxnKNWXo49JfyiPWSalIklU6X92F3FLqkL6k0VErQuyhynCaDCxlg8_aF8LtUI46M2qZcFPtxJQbSCoUYUWO_sBkZheE2P2B5ZSJNl5yg=w1920-h1080">&lt;/object>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-7" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-7">
Day 6
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-7" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>I rose early to check out a local mercado for breakfast. I tried some empanadas
at a place called La Guerita purely because the long line out front. It must be
good if locals are lining up right? It did not disappoint!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/A6H4YTifJGe9qTSi6">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEVPpnATRXqxGC3Zr8zaCUq9l24rd2_-rzlWrqK25KJOoJea29jeKGe8DRaCj3nj_r6O9M4rjyQBSioA3bJ0gUD2PW-mZ7ftCwIeRsPWHpGYoUjHDuUgWHG8-Yqwzcj44zcZlPZe4Wmq4unc2c1YIHrv=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Desayunos" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
This was also sort of a free day where we visited the mercados to try some
delacies such as Chapulin (crickets) and the Mayodormo chocolatier. The last
evening I went to a late night Chicharron taqueria near the accomidation.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-8" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-8">
Day 7
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-8" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>This day involved getting up and heading to the ADO bus station in Oaxaca. The
bus system in Mexico is pretty impressive and ADO is the regional bus service in
this part of the country. I took the bus to Mexico City which was around 8 hours
total. Thu bus made no stops, but that is okay because there is a restroom
onboard. However, I wish I had brought something besides bread!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/X7wL6BWiUMCDmDHw7">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEXeyihEEvNpoPlieOR_XKmM1d5pyaAucvlMIkBH3kP0zYhH2MJR5LWYA7r3vd2OdrBD2tAaGAd2ZwOFG2YMwi0HGw5o-qGA_F9pCsvD3kP99aMCXJAE9HeaDsjkKruXPbAYNohjePhuVZFfy4Q5BdR3=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="ADO Bus" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>The journey to CDMX was very scenic and featured mountains, desert, countryside
and everything in between. The bus was a great way to see the countryside of
Mexico that you would otherwise be flying across. I recommend these busses for
your travel in MX!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
When I arrived in CDMX, it was at the TAPO station. It is connected with the
CDMX metro so I bought a system card that I could fill with money for use in
trains and bus. This way I could easily get around town and to the next
accommodation our group was staying. I reached the accommodation and found a nice
hamburguesa place and relaxed for the day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Here is a link to the entire photo album: &lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/j8w9h7WGT7L3MSbH9">https://photos.app.goo.gl/j8w9h7WGT7L3MSbH9&lt;/a>
And videos: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Om4eJX381oc&amp;amp;list=PLVXoDcbm8YOw7WKfiBtx8pKDWlLG7p_AV">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Om4eJX381oc&amp;amp;list=PLVXoDcbm8YOw7WKfiBtx8pKDWlLG7p_AV&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item><item><title>Mexico Trip - Part 2 CDMX</title><link>https://bagnaram.github.io/posts/2022-08-13-mexico2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://bagnaram.github.io/posts/2022-08-13-mexico2/</guid><description>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-1" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-1">
Arrival in CDMX
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-1" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>My first day in CDMX was with our group and we planned a breakfast and a time to
explore a mercado called Mercado de Artisinal. We were staying in the Condesa
area near Chapultepec, which seems to be more of a classy part of the city but
it is divided by large boulevards with nice trees and paths. My friends and I
were headed towards El Centro, where the Artisinal market was. We would stop for
breakfast somewhere along the way. After journeying for a little while we
stumbled into a very home-like restaurant called Restaurant Meson Del Kajon.
This breakfast was a traditional meal of bread(pan) and various topping. I had
the huevos &amp;amp; mole and it was a nice hearty breakfast meal!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/ps1A2PqwgezjkzX68">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEX3nQWZspMytiKwVo6dl7Fdm2P342LHhxRuxmtojf1F1NFCDHcffkHFYDDJyqwp356C6lYzl8eOUnfBDr0Cq99oJzHVa6YwvxauTbHxiH382kOVioW8u4wwOx4iDTkSwrtyMcTiWbBEG6JtIPyEzYH2=w1170-h877-no?authuser=0"
alt="Huevos" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
After the meal we walked through the Artisinal Market. This place is a vast
marketplace with small vendors selling everything from pottery, to trinkets and
dishes. We split off and each of us explored the mercado. At this point it
started raining very hard and I wanted to pick out some house numbers made of
ceramic tile. these type of house numbers are famous and are a nice touch to add
onto your building. With the rain pouring harder, we decided to leave and head
back to our accommodation. At this juncture, I walked back and stopped in a nice
panaderia I found along the way back.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/VXRPLGZdUBvwunj59">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HWP2OU85oysQVNnP3YQRox7qK3QV3NjbHVgxtLCYXz0ffadqlS2M-bLUWkwnKXgszl6YHIuSUVwPRzrqL8VbdCCvFm_f_7ZCjM5I3aePa3q00lqJ2r-sV3gervRKEpRNyk2fslFBviLz2Wv02SpdxwO7-b02aAk2_spzFbLncuIHD6X2tVzU2azmP-A6MpxeM6I5QYhSpJUeNL_VmsMTM7w6oSB4Tun_HCpxjakXgr6j2dSVJcxPKHFZunSqwfIYXpoqHEe4h06r6wsI8K7xSk1dohBkOjVf8vXP0e9JXGhxeROR1AKyglphcxApEVzUhKiyqODNCKIGqKRBLNrfEP5e_glKZSfEEEN4ca83mu4ZXCA6n7LyWcTK7-ILfnlUL16jMeeJc14dAvpeaPuHHudLF5i4QKAAYaflQeVZb9ZFDj2lpGPXfdQ72jhv4hs2F9OXeqPSZE0mddEFrdzltyUoZ-t_70DbnOGkVh8LUsnBDSxJ0qWTqidAkkjR2DKjyeEM0osdb20ZIdgaakPhvs03IgMjw2NnLWUrQTAIPcu4iyK0XssfUz2gbICpH47xgAQbHjcQgB9V3B_wEEskQK1ugOU03tb6-PEb0VV8yy9HW2YhuMK3kUvFdTC1Vrw-jW1DxBRb7b24JlIKFVOJwLjVci8VbwE8EO-Ua1wv-xXJneBypQb-JYyokgWtFNrykC8EqYUp77kI4HijbmPMSmo9XKnldTIFpwMCiRuiY7XLi_hLeA-CV7fx-tY=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Panaderia" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-2" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-2">
Teoticuan Pyramids
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-2" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>We started this day very early because we would be taking a tour to the ancient
pyramids near Mexico City. The tour bus would meet us at 6:30AM and we would
journey to the pyramids and take a full tour in the morning before the place
would get too busy.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/rayarqG6Jb939hDX8">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/mbhSEcCunMPEoaQaj46jGCFRqrtZy6AoTSlXGnhdyvOYVmp7qjJ6UXffDakyrz9Jh91Y1DhRYpjyBCyPWH8zzhgsW7Jf9d--nW6Mi8yrU0LqwoAhYYdhwSLLsYy6p3PzUcLMCMc0pPR86rIQ95a0l7l8eTDxLr5h4Z7sP_nLleHcjPdtRreSOWJ02VAeG6Ft4LM_6mhEXP43hfaWxX9UsczjCLYrLUoALTHJrzuf-xKv-Nw-h10jun7Dn-NKK_3aJ6YHHWCeiZ62U5saaikYx2COQyzEJwg0b8y00-ugg7InQjTlH_Y0_Mn_E2meet5lIfBcOHqAWXayTZA-Wk72-BxZS-Yrq7oejectyPpyEjeYOb_xqrUgNUKATrRE7SLhClqTJ6c8O1xVKcL9x61mdQ7mHTL4n92WIQb3K1-qQMFjdPa5cRn91U27yGyM_N3ZPlcY-kTb9hZzL6mKkTENBUbbxdp7fwIbiHjZs5d8cfPTx52f_DE7iwNZIqLAkB7i8uofOOiewyj6aM4ikoaBfKMDffkf7g5inXEyT9W1RevyDBqNxtPj_edNbfW59AD9MMM_lAscrsWIfpx01M-8C_q8XAjPqZXgTcuZYA0j8W49bPVvtg7gp8BG_NTfYEd4JmjcOgz5F_JWv1i10iWhraqdan-jiAllZKGRvT6XTEVFzLtwnTXuEdfQjZVT9VQiD2jNpGIeUEn0CrNqoYf6Quobh0Yec_RvCgqv7hV6sjNoeosMawePtDpG0-g=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Teoticuan" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
As we arrived, the morning sky was dotted with many hot-air balloons. It appears
that separate tours are available to take you up to see the pyramids from great
heights! As we unloaded and entered the park, we saw the pyramid scene for the
first time. These were built over the course of hundreds of years with varying
layers and Adonis over the years, displaying a sort of shell of pyramid layers.
They were magnificent and the Sun and Moon pyramids dominated the scene. It was
fun to imagine thousands of people walking the plazas and living in this space
as it was so peaceful to see in the morning. Shortly the crowds arrived and
changed the feel of the place. But in a good way, because it gave a bustling and
city feel to the area. As we toured these ruins, the guide explained some of the
history including the Aztecs finding this ancient civilization seemingly
abandoned. Then the Spanish entering and making their print on the place.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="512" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/ypFYopUzqp8" title="Pyramids" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;p>
After the tour we had lunch at a restaurant on the grounds of the park area with
some live mexican Norteno music which made a great scene! After we finished we
reached back to CDMX and the rest of the day was open for me. My friends would
be having dinner at a chef&amp;#39;s tasting, but I opted to free my time and try out a
famous al pastor taco place. This place was an automotive garage during the day,
and served street tacos at night. The ultimate and unlikely combination that I
had to try. It was about an hour walk from our accommodation in Candenza, and I
wanted to walk around and see some of the city as well. A nice walk later, I
found some of the most delicious al-pastor at the walk-up restaurant called El
Visito. It did not disappoint, with flavorful meat and salsas to top the tacos!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/ZZPVrtL6VeNTz1jZA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/HX4KRd19anWXUR1Uw4a8_TW3kfFio2BUkvbFG1tyXpyk1yTx1WNaA7RRjXYRpgXcD5Q4Ie4w56iHSaRZNmy203vbIXA1T6q7fjfurtBIHFuEDQhxxpMVZ0JvO3b4rfaJLMw1LTSIap3R7fwT99QL-E3g6mOVsrWLUHvDEWKbyt7qESSxuQDyS0LLXZwpkG1Zdquc5WDcnY2Gzw2A0NRfnVF6kZjcrZVQbmGNLaIzgu7H_fauO9vPNANCIRYynj8rw1hhHNtcSmoN5pT9zDhgThY14vCRpp-T_IbSXH06eQ6K6Rwmfc1_PoASx7bZLNHcntruVS4U3VxXihz2f79V8z03gRkepZOSPWVl6XkhHo3o6vD-46pGj_g6vp-9vAZbbtyGq2hHv0uzxS35SZNbHET_AZ-1U9AeZQA-JPc03_hh6VUxNbhq4cCBIGC0LPjJBfUb-WRgdDmvMLVIayY7DIXrU4ZLRvo6ASXVgH06EDdmt2fQjsKM76x2tVmwHgPMkAnkkKAJU5EV2Im44xz9juO0hyG15CmKTV9ciVazBJbGgBXuX0PFTgi8ONguCLEle9bAen8ldYfYSNq_WEyW7Rjvr4P-CnwmNW9ObTSfKzB8CGDASD3vBLIPfUbVibrS1l65OhJX8p2jdxK4Hgz37ZsrkQcnTrKnBOVtrDE_ImECp_ts_kIqMrIsKZm5uSHZS5ngpL0jd1f25MryPOoWmgXvXkQdPjr6pk7C40vgZ_2jS5-3T0NHcPF_fzE=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Los Mejores Al Pastor" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
I walked back and stopped at a nice mezcaleria called Neicos. This place was one
of my highlights. I stumbled into the place and met some incredibly nice and
hospitable folks there. What a nice place to become a regular. What appears like
a liquor store on the bottom level, a staircase leads you to a middle level
mezcal bar, and rooftop on the 3rd level. I would make this mezcaleria a regular
stop during my time in CDMX!&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-3" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-3">
Mercados
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-3" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>The next day my friends and I would explore Mercado Sonora in CDMX. We planned
the journey over cafe at a place nextdoor to our accommodation with a very
friendly owner. Mercado Sonora isn&amp;#39;t the place for everyone. If you are
sensitive to animal treatment including tight spaces and cages I would skip this
one. We mainly went to this mercado to see some of the new-age and religious
items for sale. These include incense, paper masks, and an assortment of bootleg
dollar store items. As a cartoon fan, we saw many un-sanctioned Sonic the
Hedgehog merchandise that I could not resist. At this market one of my friends
experienced our closest shady moment in which she was given change from a vendor
containing a counterfeit bill. We only discovered this after she attempted to
make a purchase with one of the bills.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/jQaYxY7XRQxHre3v9">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/FW___JxUraQswQZ0AplPVIUkUcPbXNIDoVzgWUAkEqOaTbV1ujYBpI8lyO3FEoJ_hsR_M4qs10c2BTv3Xq6jf93Xsx4rB2JveraJ4QAyxfuyY9xnYLrWAefJuKkfgcCURUAst0q0f-A-r_vrJtRahJayVRa-VSkY4xVRk10Bnc9nQhRgIscBxpXVEuD121fsrMMp0HMdrfzAegxvBgnXIVpF8NubRlGtf3Fnvx8aQUC_FIAE3JZKE73oNe9taMYcNcX49wtIgWAMC5cX_CxneUdK8PHwq4fwbg6VU5Ajl-qQ_FJpxU-wIxC-62GiTGAgBJYngiGDsgckkOX-OrrgXEio9wCZ5aY6la-gnqXDBc_Lq4X8iu-lPF1czspyfgTaXgRGKNFapMIApM3fEud0L2-CSRLwZ3x8oWWOuGEhgIOt-2vdq3rKgN7bi-Z7dbUlIWoUy-IBSz6tflHWwWYi_CIzyE3FaJGsKrvfKmx-z1yufhJ39ybzNNHOMZpFywLKaNM5TJre78N1itnPawZzlmN-p8k89guQpx_wvFXpnoqnCgY07KWdfgNMiPrPQAU-Q3rOJBbgtWaxpsNChQ9t0oAfENxR-wiHUbqcGBydazl1YCg85pGlYfpVZBvPlbsCkKvGiP_Pr2u0scQsamxmt9mUYNsbBOiJcFBpo9eMOy78IAhNrJOqm-EhTUwh1X1SlcX4mMJ7o7rKKt-nns4-V29yhnKDsoiaCbm35xfM5jPpB89eu0VeNPLlEiM=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Sonora" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
After exploring Sonora, we ventured to an adjacent Mercado de la Merced that was
more of a household goods and street food market. This place was massive. If you
get a thrill of feeling lost in a seemingly endless labyrinth of marketplace
vendors in a tight space, this is the place for you! I fall into this category
and quickly went into sensory overload with the sheer size of the place. We were
on the hunt for Pazole. This is a soup like thing served on only the weekends.
It contains bone broth, vegetables and maiz. We searched and searched and
eventually found a place called Cocina Frida. Very tasty and flavorful!
Afterwards we exited the chaotic market and a friend bought some chicharrones
and we headed to the Zocolo area.&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="512" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/r9ZJeezGyrU" title="Mercado Sonora" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/zJdR5qaFXFiEwD4v6">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/6cge64Q6X785qt4b25o0ONoQyKw7uhO-TbpV-qzYfSwpFD7s6JPaVKP__MmQjm5b93-4s5zYO-Y5h7rGED5CU-AHKM3IiFI2kEhXnVjWZaJQ_-daBcr4-KwNJZ4ZSOJh8YceekwH5itRF7Q5PotmzeMzuaHXgcn2eNLrqbkwPUFUSGLLvsSV4nmoY1C8WuSo3GlnGrP8O6eiyHXkFcGyBBWO_5W1HVJf45_GS40BNkXR_8u1jamVCqE6GU0-VarABxn0l2AN_m1mfcHy-Jsb7HJmL8-VsyrWQtuMUo4f9_WGZi4VkA6JIJYxtlAx1356d9HZYRt7fcnVzwljJk5riP3mHhMnapD_z2W4w62Yzk77V0U8qJgYXTJQQLYt3c4QpBZYu7XJ1W0QjT6hjQAZJEOPK8eKvTv0HGm7jsjTuD-lVWfwR6Y_I6jMIaAS9tQhDiAu7VJTliE-aT1n1xoSUifwUJdgDgDIbWv0B6Ls624mS6IiuK6SxAnols6bjVyDoA5xS0j0Zh5ovPaXneBIN8RX8SnVEhl14pnaHJVkf99vnHBKRKWoVWUfvkoAlp0QHkbVw-GMI0v0f0noRE-TbYkAbXiI86aivnFqknkFYbu27tjyDUMQpfipBBeKcOk3vxgjqmPe5l6sOfdlVAqd9xFpItXqczteU9cJqUoWzCAvl-mIB1Ja8r_CgJxdBNvAsutcJvt54FVIeY2sL_7PiYlQsZE7rDHKtzxFSk4QCFY3Y-Bc_9zoNhmnzBA=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Cocina Frida" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
Zocolo was the main town square with the church and main city plaza. The
architecture is incredible in the region. Here you can clearly see the
construction made from volcanic stone for the buildings. We explored some of the
buildings, walked the city streets and even visited a mercado with some famous
exotic animals and insects.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/vU71yWiiCGfPg45A7">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/1-XpyeIqGBPW1401juRaXuoMNHA3VqG2ABd843hCsZ_BEmWkNE_vrgpnB8fxm3OqB6NpbSTl39FId9EzXK4FX_zVLoerjaMs0syyPwoJl5Bh-GDkziuHDT4OpbtGYYs-tyZSgIBx1CvO4Vt3Lya7-D8Sv58T_xnBviE3bHG_gBFBvMwnudOPkZeRfoAVJCrx5ElFZjckod8EehBA3X52MEri4vFVGn6PJhWxsBqs_6QYbMVUOSTn2FdHf2uzED-0PTQkDzkKr-z4wZFpApGZbLBg2I8CHCN97VntqiAUNgbUBrAhdyjacHl4s5cFjTIKlEmBq7YdQEygtZ7cvXVxN5eyzMR8xa_t_oVdN_g4oT9yH0j7yzGpNP9nAPcHoZ58cNYTzWog3GylU-x-UOvN5bLnxkHc4YBbHsc5_wOzeCxXrr6VKRFClvBC6rQJANPgx-IYWQ1-dZv0mUDcDTa_gcXXFf4mqrrFz0tcSDAMSOOV7oR5J8OLM61jyXzZDLLGIbQZ254y_q7Ev3e3WCkTW09vnvHtUQr99Qqw3EltX-HQi5NacRID0mVXJYc8QWLXZWJ_0RCEzLh5zD5V6VMsAAPa3OmQcwLX_gFrv8-a3x2GhAWEjTfm81kkB7xLWgixafM1V2AqYjb69dW2NcXzIyT9P39IRSFB9Fb2m2Ja_FpBAvsMRSXRkSp-7Ef0o7szkqIzjnYPhMrOQB4T5gKKbuZ__LbSwYLNH5FMGTxzntBUTGMIiEiGxGgv4wQ=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Zocolo" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-4" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-4">
Last(maybe) Day
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-4" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>This day was supposed to by my last for the trip but unfortunately due to a
travel agency mishap, the trip got extended. For better or worse I found myself
with an extra week in CDMX. This was also partly due to the fact that my pet
sitter was still staying in my house so I didn&amp;#39;t really have anyplace to go back
to just yet. With these additional days left for the trip I planned with a
couple other friends who were also staying over a few more days. I ended up
losing the majority of this day to logistics and going to and from the airport.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
This evening we visited the Garibaldi area, traditionally known for the
mariachi. Now many locals consider this area a tourist trap, and we were aware
ase we were continually approached by the singers on the street of the plaza.
They typically ask to sing you a song and will take payment per cancion. We
decided to skip the plaza and go straight to a restaurant that offered
legitimate mariachi bands at the table. We ordered ourselves some micheledas and
requested a few canciones like Guadalajara for the absolute genuine experience.
La authentica musica Mexicana! After this place we went to a few other clubs for
their music nights. They had performers doing the traditional rancheras like a
Antonio Aguilar and Vincent Fernandez impressions! We sang along that night and
it was a real nice, although tourist way to enjoy the night!&lt;/p>
&lt;iframe width="100%" height="512" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/MDBztidG6RA" title="Michelada" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen>&lt;/iframe>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/ukq3wF4JuAzwZtGd9">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/PDFHXaeAdLXQ4Ko9yl9nKpX1ZFF_xWXjYnuEB6UNI6dH25W-91HPQ4ANG2zWyIdWKJsOYZLX9-b81As_NVO3k-ypsdGH6B9qIKn0UJDg0nPcYri2FkUC302QAAjWXMdsHpPqtPgbhiUU0BhNz8_Vu9b-QjtL-c70zzjeOUFbN7y5vRIkTs1uxDCRnl2wH5kyN49XWmejfcH6rpZGDGfgrg9BeygJi_jqpvSvL_-z0LFl6gsOSjcrG3l3-26joovZiwMzUDtdWHKA3oGp00bMKBinVdXno4-M-xe9v0U0AGhPyHAfbaXFRZa5pUZtbp61pHpgqqj7U6HtFKRoH7gpEgE8EwL6SHQxZUJ79sZ-Cs0hnb2U5isnTcMFGtBl9Re9fRILrX3VKUnUkPkIWTvrKt7CuXKJAt9UdtOliFah9YGqjmjWDINHIa4-C0kGMYyPakldIEeyvwmJP66Sp0LOPeTzS7EK4cp1B3j_4lfRU-tPEB5uM0DL1qJYR34nJ8ATdd30BSVOudVtCkJQ7tj6w408urKj6rNz7sxF5bAKBT5SVzc4TX-_EzGiVR6lvbHd6RGZJMHiWFwasLoiTIsuwDXjcp7xKpmx_ynQBmGJzbuYRu9c_TMmCrvGUhwttD4QApM3uw4IZD70mh4WgTfV8EDT_b4xS7elLcAq0qsiCjtfqGeT2qVt_Qga5jBRu_TrfbhD9IcGQnNvbx61vC8GpiFJpPvb_BkX1ZVppGB6m3vwxhs9zlWSyAh4Yr8=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Mariachi" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-5" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-5">
The Rest
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-5" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>The remainder of the week I worked during the dag so not as much time to
explore. I found a hostel called Roomies that was a quieter place but I really
liked it because it was not a party hostel and felt more laid back there. The
lady working there was very nice and she even walked me around the city to see
the plaza monument!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
I was able to fill this week by visiting the Bosque de Chapultepec, a large
castle situated on a hill in the park. This amazing palace was adorned with
murals and marble and stone work and very pleasant gardens to walk through.
Definitely a must-see in CDMX!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/YbYmcgwzMj9PU67y5">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/xRAdeq_4R6MMsVD05r_8xwWAJPtzf5wb1_VHit4n82xdSc_6HhRarVleU7wSGHQ8cixMca4_S8Y5K2LyKW9rcCt6_u8cQsoNX4bBNG4GL2oI-cCCKA1C5oQ9WIAaYZpEVb8pP0ebmN2KVlVtOSC7CCX3gPiF6KA-CFwPFA6EkeVwwesXinGnbWgaz-HYLnkH4OmkrNmaoS3572wXysxQz5cWqvE3l5S7A8r-ew2us-tQPaJCPL06pJHe3yB9yVbuoewPQLuG51C4Sh52YdrEkLy_lqaLuR5jt9sqXUq51696RGDZBllA-rMrgrFSBnD_bw750PK9qkiPyi2yS9JLplXIvlB-GN981lHmbG2HUCYASI4ktBp4Hf23uP1Ucg-tiZTWDGFWyWHtgLMeTTgAW6eftd9jtvfp7_5lYKd_PZZ4ZUfyqokJJLBewU-aSnPMjZlSy_Z_MA6agFHILjXiNLi2MpeVrB9h8mqFfDY-oxbezMN3iZkLP5GPRSgfNQ0KAaHtYPWSkFGErfK-JMkWO1WLdI_ZhK6Llsn-lLrImXxahUeLgq6d0bqO2TKmMo0PphfWhJtSw0OQ32u2cJNPMWNllTdlwH675kqt4vahl1dG8aPZ0ALV5VvZINTHSf8j8uKcQrJaDorfjlzlKv-Wf_FYmapiM30rNSVyD4tDJpGRt2iQwcvtsC8Xj2rDjb_9Xy6DvRFWmmDR6e5B0OTVMb_2pEn4bEVix2WRW_Js_EYgXn8m_bbf5Lvk-Ns=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Chapultepec" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
We also visited a few very fascinating speak-easy taverns in the city that offer
drinks that are works of art themselves. The showmanship of mixing the drinks
was remarkable to watch. Clearly a talent that I never appreciated until seeing
it this moment!&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/UPqzwkeG7uyJWNy2A">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEVVhtn2DpLsnvYpHrS7Yp2mfafx6LGOvUkrOuG6Q9hZQ-QEbPeZinordx33vB_wAWyouYtpkKQlI0eZqxNAs4AYiMQjFUelVFz4llgrHwOY4KvZsipHGr1roShhqBf-ugPXL9EWER56ro4MwYeV57cn=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
I spent the days working and sometimes visiting lunch places before returning to
work the afternoon. Of note, I visited a Columbian cafe called Pollos Mario that
had delicious pan de bono! I also visited a vegan taco place one day that had
killer pineapple and eggplant tacos!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
The final tours of the trip were a Tepito tour, though a fierce district that
clearly has a way about itself! Here I was able to appreciate the core and soul
of this district with a friendly although misunderstood history. The mercado
there was massive and they are known for their exotic micheladas topped with
gummies, salts and sugar. These drinks were delicious delicacies. I had some of
my most delicious street tacos here including some liver tacos tucked away in a
stall.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/sbtWHMyMLY15t8an9">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEUkCqIBK9gcvUtqPUjXKnLHjV8qDA4TTIHUGU4cCYqKNzOUHEukbP9vjIi6NXb_26H-bhdOVkhia7lGpB_f1XS2_Wn74LkDHdT3hnudtnEBGmk91JwIfn_Dbg77Bcpn-RH8a4AzR3ydNmuVqymSiX5Q=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Tepito Street Food" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/UnELT27cN1MYWQYq7">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/MEsGH06-3ofHNb6H17we2TiFMgBwwIPQBoqzmpXAGCro14MhbPhzwArlfOZOrKZpnJlrsSTDzJafM9ml99bvdKMi5QNgnV3iSexBU0ssv8oPr1255PSs88FKWMctRUZn0KG0B4-gxwc91Ikz7lCacxApC2JrzhqHt4v7pmjaPRgB8upZbEu-RE3VRFUu7noix_LX05qM00xm32PjrChU2JbRQHhAtfSE5BM1AekF1Sqwhjw0Ip3gbaUnCHHePWevfNg9-KRYBpCp1rrhrztirR-Utsee-Rq3RSQG1RjvAP9EtN8vSlJ5ihXJQ9NxhluljI8CnJwu7ulZU6z3w5PTZqJl7bbpaCIY0aOx9UNJQmWWwFT6MoY9lVWuE2J1GWJxO8bOnXykfLvY5PCS1qtKuY88pcuig_MFzsP6ovWdAENALoWzrTDlIOmw8Gc-H_JWZSYcCwGY9xzAkB5MXr23FUvJOZQZkyc8fabCuOcRb5SBXQmsDw0UzIBID1AP1fbhgfVsWcmFf2cZi3ZFAT5ptSSeADqdRJRqbM7aI4iWIvK0j-3g8CgJyN_92AiyPLVpHVdhQtvjlr-CrpIK43JVImrg3wgr8z7ZteyFm36_aD53udom614WcQG6hAIq8DeFEsarNFk0Rj5UmexIyDKrsb8lFJcOoaPpA-0oDTVjHfo8VLsxv0iMrvQgG7c0369hgFlP5gqti-stpojwv7iwwPeF4MtqPxDdEnHpENbjirEkFm2sediPg8qe_Tc=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Tepito" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/qXyoaYM2PSLfo1KJA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/pw/AL9nZEVuvPHE6Y3L5KCNR6-1xEN5yBTlRqerbOIuOMDtZJXlciCV7KNvCIHtTe03iYx_E_fAS63EfT59e5TK5wTL0-UlF03gEcnpFhyiRjUoWdumZ-QYYFH6n302HBs9KjkQlPgEaUOv3JCuOkHf4D6W2XUd=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Tepito Churros" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;p>
The final day of the trip featured an amazing hike tour up the Nevado de Toluka
volcano. This is a mighty way to end my Mexico trip. The trip there was around 3
hours including transfer to collectivo. Once we reached the altitude I was
immediately hit by lack of oxygen in the air. Our guide took us slowly up for
the starter until we adjusted. We spent the time climbing until reaching a rock
scramble. The final leg before the summit featured sheer breathtaking views and
some of the most amazing vistas of my trip! After the peak, we descended down a
very unstable rock path. The gravel constantly slid out underneath us making it
a treacherous trail to keep our footing. It was absolutely as exhausting going
down as it was going up! I thoroughly recommend doing this trail if you get the
chance. All in all, around 8 hours total and we reached the city after stopping
for a nice dinner.&lt;/p>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/MvddvMHhVuGALmqLA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/NXujLdkvfQwi1kyAtCbIVf4UAxSRcpZyCEHwjcAyFedxNATWWn-JROaxgiwRA93d2I3c8MuTMcYPPnu_QjMnGi3lDpwXnsHR4_TxdaxfwyssaS2KicVruQHRdhwTGbf1Eziu3CfRJfxHGGx8dX57RpJ5QUpS9HQ9_BajwbOXt1fL8ITKY8z1jhnK6GTS_xjzvmh3MaOL8GKIhONz7flgkPDFQhoHgcZUp-CLtRnINT9gztFMllbeyj810Q5O5V4oyL8sOwtY6jUi0_3uz-MvzGpWthAOCyWtf1SQTDn-vTwcslReB46pVZkTBxh00dUeoeO2SEdkR03R-mIFpN8E8FGGAn4r8V-dcm1wOV-W6eXjd3g6bZh5nSaTOgfIqwE3vYcCmWSBL22jLz7AaYRBfZiiwvR_UKYpVpD4G6MAKM2GRyqS6STEdlrCnLYJXoggYohVdSCxJbnXdQ-6alaOT59GU-BYwnAXaRmAD-gtJKhXadGhykjLVc2awHt55A9-do8hiP-twroE3WiS8QnPp_jnUlldA1wGMgo5nmw9q674by2G5eG_H9FDI1LNvU37NZ-PqWFGu4_RsTGdq2kpNlpKy50z7yajWLQ77xKwh8aBxY74ail1WbtuU2OCwT_9fA3vhPeJQYjPfWNqju9Z9TkJkM2OpzYjr8xl-ZI1RUS8ab4ssEEadhYSa6cjK22dQk66vqL1Xnu8kN3Pt8DUWDLYQlV50M2Ri-5N01TvTuZrEMKsfTSE4NPm-CI=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Nevado de Toluka" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/LnKtK2pbGaHU4AKHA">&lt;img
src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/lAiXMUKJ7EK91i-4kjd1dgJvnnoIYuxkoRg_ZDgPnjb2krhbHA5ROIxjojUSyonxyqflcfMs2UW6knZSo-X3csGdB1CmZnJdkx1AyIyVWP_uWlVKbb5WUMSowJ5OqwggzfWOtl0dCwPKMw7VdbnEsZ1dn9LoB3I1LY_WdHNoattp3YFWRvnl23X9Wuh1nwQdDfv9SWtyb-YAVPM27mZVCkmf-sZPEM1b1vV835hRB9YoxYMUwcVPQbGB-TMJ60ZTYCNBOsF_N-q9NBxlBXanB7C6P9b8MELB7IrtdBhtwPz9PgJdX_qEZHEKFGkZ13_Oht-epvNYfHSNNpiyFeZhupodmVlr0g2kPYEjTh_iJ7TVc_c--1dTaNJktF7_Qz-VIcINsy_Zw1mhl9l4cpMaeyLwo6abv55BArJdFey5GjsrfYATeOytGM0ui6aB9oHHvw9ZaJ6YSjlx2waMCGIZu-TVyDoNmP61TPHHwuXuUP4mFuAAaWI8qFWNBLifGeZUO2Yigr930VWLXyBc_LFOmFl9BsevCdsqcLPel4UKuEVdIO0bEU4skBAt0MBSBXJeBjkvHfG5VmwwOwqtF1ZFQvgQBwGhU5PjI8iOak1SAryGmFxQR7Yv3Avh4beSJ12SiLXvov1jKHrdzAmJa6LgJR3cCej9ps1Qa4sJcbJnJm5bRL3NzSzAeeC1j6QeQQQaynv8MmoX-GANNleE6L-Yflwf6WwPYkF3oGr3dMtZH2JwzQdhGVMim7hxU3M=w1172-h879-no?authuser=0"
alt="Final Michelada" class="inline"/>&lt;/a>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>
&lt;div id="outline-container-headline-6" class="outline-2">
&lt;h2 id="headline-6">
Conclusion
&lt;/h2>
&lt;div id="outline-text-headline-6" class="outline-text-2">
&lt;p>This first trip to Mexico was amazing. Should you go? YES. Skip the tourist
spots in Mexico and go straight to the heart of culture and meet the people of
the region. I made some lasting connections that I hope to stay in touch with
and perhaps plan trips again to see them! This trip broke many impressions we
have of MX and I grew a lot during this trip and hope to come back soon. There
is so much more than what you hear on the news and until seeing the place for
myself, I would have lived in that same fear too. Certainly a trip I won&amp;#39;t ever
forget!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
Link to entire photo album: &lt;a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/YWhSFGKTFCdfd3hz9">https://photos.app.goo.gl/YWhSFGKTFCdfd3hz9&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;/div></description></item></channel></rss>